Guide to the American Social Science Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Association records, 1863-1906; Series I; 4.75' (12 boxes)
  - Departmental records
    - Health
      - Detroit meeting: transcript, 1875 May (Box 10, Folder 220-221)
      - General correspondence See also: General correspondence, post-1871: D.L. Lincoln, 1873-1880 (Box 11, Folder 222-224)
      - Circulars and invitations, 1874-1876, undated (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - Essay contest
        - Correspondence, 1869-1871, undated (Box 11, Folder 226)
        - Entries, 1871, undated (Box 11, Folder 227-230)
      - Topical files
        - medical, general, 1869-1870, undated (Box 11, Folder 231)
        - nurses' training, 1862, 1867-1874, undated (Box 11, Folder 232)
        - treatment of the insane, 1862-1892, undated (Box 11, Folder 233)
    - Clippings, 1876, undated (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - Jurisprudence
      - Reports to Executive Committee, 1869-1873 (Box 11, Folder 235)
      - Committee on Education in Jurisprudence, 1869-1870 (Box 11, Folder 236)
      - Topical files: civil service reform, 1868-1870, undated (Box 11, Folder 237-238)
    - Social Economy
      - Report to the president, 1876 (Box 12, Folder 239)
      - Topical files: building associations and codes, 1875-1877, undated (Box 12, Folder 240-242)
    - Unidentified departments
      - lists, papers, notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 243)
      - topical files, 1863-1902, undates (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Publications, 1965-1874, 1890, undted (Box 12, Folder 245-246)
- Related association records, 1865-1889; Series II; .50' (1 box)
  Series includes records for the Boston Social Science Association, the British Association for the Promotion of Social Science, the Conference of Charities and Correction, and the Boston Branch of the National Anti-Inflation League. For all but the Conference of Charities and Correction, these associations are each represented in the records by a single folder, which may contain scattered minutes, correspondence, and printed material. For the Conference of Charities and Corrections, however, the records include several folders of correspondence, mainly between Sanborn and individuals affiliated with state boards of charity. The correspondence is again fragmentary, with the most substantial correspondence dating from 1873-1878 and from 1886-1887. These records are generally concerned with arrangements for the conference's meetings, papers to be delivered, and orders and payment for meeting proceedings.
  The records in this series are arranged in alphabetical order by association name.
  - Boston Social Science Association, 1865 (Box 13, Folder 247)
  - British Association for the Promotion of Social Science, 1866, 1869, 1873-1874 (Box 13, Folder 248)
  - Conference of Charities and Correction (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1873-1879 (Box 13, Folder 249)
      - General, 1886-1889 (Box 13, Folder 250)
      - Barrows, Isabel C., 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 251)
      - Chace, George, 1876-1878, undated (Box 13, Folder 252)
      - Chapin, William W., 1873-1878 (Box 13, Folder 253)
      - Fanning, James O., 1876-1878 (Box 13, Folder 254)
      - Giles, H. H., 1874-1878, 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 255)
      - Harrison, George L., 1873-1874 (Box 13, Folder 256)
      - Hart, H. H., 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 257)
      - Hoyt, Charles S., 1874-1878 (Box 13, Folder 258)
      - Lord, Henry W., 1874-1878 (Box 13, Folder 259)
      - Luther, Dillon, 1874-1878 (Box 13, Folder 260)
      - Neff, William, 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 261)
      - Ohio, State of. Executive Department. Board of State Charities, 1878, 1887 (Box 13, Folder 262)
      - Ourt, A. J., 1874-1877 (Box 13, Folder 263)
      - Pennsylvania, Commonwealth of. Board of Public Charities
        See: box 13, folder 256 See: box 13, folder 260
      - Rhode Island, State of. Board of State Charities and Corrections
        See: box 13, folder 252 See: box 13, folder 253
      - State Charities Aid Association, 1874-1877, 1887 (Box 13, Folder 264)
      - Wines, Frederick H., 1873-1876, 1885 (Box 13, Folder 265)
      - Wisconsin, State of. State Board of Charities and Reform, 1873-1878, 1886 (Box 13, Folder 266)
        See also: box 13, folder 255
    - Saratoga meetings, 1876, 1877 (Box 13, Folder 267)
    - Thirteenth National Conference. Treasurer's records (Box 13)
      - General, 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 268)
      - Requests for copies of proceedings, 1886-1887, undated (Box 13, Folder 269-271)
      - Payment records for proceedings, 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 272-273)
  - National Anti-Inflation League. Boston Branch, 1874-1875 (Box 13, Folder 274)